Medical appointments would be scheduled during business hours, and I knew that I would need time off to recover from surgical procedures. Again, being a typical lawyer, I had done my due diligence on what to expect from treatment. Admittedly, a lot of that was through Doctor Google, perhaps not my best move and I wouldn't recommend that. (Laughter) But while I was ready for all the physical side effects, what really scared me was this thing called chemo brain. Chemo brain presents itself through memory loss, an inability to concentrate and an inability to solve problems. And if this happened to me, I wondered how I was going to do my job as a lawyer. Would I be forced to leave work? And how could I possibly have a discussion with my manager about reasonable adjustments to my working arrangements when I didn't know how I was going to be impacted? I was fortunate to have a supportive manager who was happy to see how things went as we went along, rather than requiring a concrete plan up front. I was lucky that while he may not have even known about this concept of reasonable adjustments, to him, it was just common sense. But I've learned that it's not common sense to everyone. Everyone going through treatment will learn how it impacts them and what their limitations are. And they'll learn to adjust for that. So for me, there were the tips and tricks that I learned about the treatment itself, like, before you go to chemo, you need to make sure you're really well hydrated and that you're warm, because it helps the nurses to find your veins. And make sure that you don't eat any of your favorite food, either before or after chemo, because you're going to be throwing that up and you won't ever want to look at it again. (Laughter) I learned that one the hard way. And then there were the tricks for managing my workflow. I scheduled chemo for first thing on a Monday morning. I knew that from the time I left the cancer care unit, I had about four hours before this fog screen would come down and I would start to be sick. So I would use that time to clean my inbox and make any urgent calls. The worst of the sickness would be gone within about 48 hours. And then I would log back into work from home. This treatment continued and I knew what to expect. I was able to set reasonable expectations with my business partners about what I could do and the time frames that I could do it in. But I still remember the hesitation in their voices when it came to asking for things. And asking me to do things by a certain time. And trust me, these were people that were not afraid of setting a good deadline. (Laughter) I got the impression they didn't want to put any extra pressure on me while I was going through treatment. And while I appreciated the sentiment, I actually needed the deadlines. To me, that was something within my control and something that could stay in my control when there were so many things that couldn't. And as I was working from home, I was thinking about how employers should be applying this concept of reasonable adjustments in our current age, where one in two Australian men and women will be diagnosed with cancer by the age of 85. So, as we continue to work longer and longer into older age, the chances of having a serious illness while we're in the workforce are increasing. And with technology enabling us to work anywhere, any time, reasonable adjustments are no longer contingent upon whether or not you can continue to physically make it into the physical office. Reasonable adjustments are also not about just offering a longer break or a comfier chair to sit in, although those things might be good, too. At the very least, we need to be applying the flexibility policies and strategies we've developed for other scenarios, like for people with family responsibilities. But how can we ensure that people are even having a conversation about what reasonable adjustments might look like for them if a manager's first response is to say, "Oh no, don't come back to work until you're better." And a light went on for me. It must be compulsory for managers to have to have these conversations with their employees. And lessons from people like me, that have really benefited from working through treatment, need to be more widely shared. And I thought about what could be done to guide these conversations, and then an amazing colleague of mine, Camilla Gunn, developed a "Working with Cancer" toolkit. The toolkit provides a framework for those diagnosed, their managers, their carers and their coworkers to have conversations about cancer and the work support available. Camilla and I have now been to other organizations to talk about the toolkit and how it can help to guide through what, quite frankly, are otherwise some pretty awkward conversations. And I'm pleased to say that the uptake of the toolkit is increasing. So what should be a manager's first response when somebody says that they're sick and they don't know how it's going to impact their work? It must be this: "To the extent that you are able, and want to, we would love to work out an arrangement for you to continue to work through treatment." We need to start positively engaging people with serious illness to keep them in the workforce, rather than paternalistically pushing them away. I've told you my story because I want you to know the benefits that working through treatment brought me. And I also want to change your perceptions if you think that somebody going through treatment is just bored, frail and vomiting a lot. And yes, these things were true some of the time, if not a lot of the time, but I was also determined to push myself at work as much as I had always done. And I was able to do that because my employer gave me the choice. Most importantly, I'm telling you because while it's a seemingly obvious choice to give someone, it's not one that is always offered or encouraged. And it must be. Thank you. (Applause)
Mes rendez-vous médicaux seraient planifiés sur les heures de travail, et j'aurais une période de convalescence après les interventions chirurgicales. Encore une fois, en tant qu'avocate, j'avais analysé tout ce qui m'attendait pendant le traitement. J'avoue, la majeure partie a été trouvée sur Google sans doute pas ma meilleure idée, je ne le recommande pas. (Rires) Mais alors que j'étais prête pour les effets secondaires physiques, ce qui m'effrayait le plus était le brouillard cérébral, qui se définit par des pertes de mémoire, des difficultés à se concentrer et une incapacité à résoudre des problèmes. Et si ça devait m'arriver, comment pourrais-je exercer mon métier d'avocate ? Devrais-je arrêter de travailler ? Et comment avoir une discussion avec mon responsable sur les arrangements dont j'avais besoin sans savoir quel effet le traitement aurait sur moi ? J'ai eu la chance d'avoir un responsable bienveillant et à l'écoute qui a accepté de prendre les choses comme elles venaient, plutôt que d'établir un plan précis dès le départ. J'ai eu la chance que, sans avoir jamais entendu parler de cette notion d'ajustements professionnels, pour lui, ça relevait juste du bon sens. Mais j'ai appris que ce n'était pas le cas pour tout le monde. Qui suit un traitement découvrira comment ça l'affecte, quelles sont ses limites et apprendra à s'adapter en fonction. J'ai appris quelques astuces par rapport au traitement lui-même comme, avant d'aller en chimio, faire attention à bien s'hydrater et à avoir assez chaud, car ça aide l'infirmière à trouver vos veines. Ne pas manger votre plat favori avant, ou après la chimio, car vous allez le vomir et en être dégoûté à vie. (Rires) Je l'ai appris à mes dépens. J'avais quelques trucs pour gérer au travail. Je planifiais ma chimio très tôt, le lundi matin, car je savais que dès que je quittais le service d'oncologie, j'avais environ 4 heures de répit avant d'avoir l'esprit embrouillé et de commencer à avoir la nausée. Donc j'utilisais ce temps pour traiter mes mails et passer les appels urgents. En 48 heures, le pire était passé et je me remettais au travail de chez moi. Le traitement a continué, mais je pouvais anticiper. J'étais capable de prévoir avec mes collaborateurs ce que je pouvais exécuter et en combien de temps. Mais j'entends encore l'hésitation dans leur voix quand ils avaient une tâche à me confier. En particulier celles avec des échéances. Et croyez-moi, c'étaient des personnes qui n'avaient pas peur de fixer des délais ! (Rires) Je sentais qu'ils ne voulaient pas me mettre la pression pendant mon traitement. Et si j'appréciais l'intention, j'avais néanmoins besoin de ces délais imposés. Car c'était quelque chose que je pouvais maîtriser et garder sous contrôle, contrairement à tant d'autres choses. Et pendant que je travaillais de chez moi, je réfléchissais à comment les employeurs devraient appliquer ce concept d'ajustements professionnels, à l'époque actuelle quand un Australien sur deux sera diagnostiqué d'un cancer avant 85 ans. Et comme nous travaillons de plus en plus vieux, les risques d'avoir une maladie grave pendant notre carrière ne cessent d'augmenter. Et avec les technologies nous permettant de travailler quand et d'où l'on veut, la question n'est plus de savoir si oui ou non, vous pouvez effectuer votre travail dans les locaux de l'entreprise. Ce n'est pas non plus autoriser une pause plus longue ou fournir une chaise plus confortable, même si ça reste appréciable. Au minimum, il faudrait pouvoir appliquer ces mesures d'assouplissement à d'autres cas de figures comme pour les personnes avec des responsabilités familiales. Mais comment pourraient-elles avoir ne serait-ce qu'une discussion sur ce qu'elles attendent en terme d'ajustements si la première réaction de leur employeur est de leur dire : « Oh non, ne revenez pas travailler jusqu'à ce que vous alliez mieux. » Et là, j'ai eu une idée. Il devrait être obligatoire pour un patron d'avoir cette conversation avec ses employés. Et les leçons de personnes comme moi qui ont travaillé en étant malade et en ont tiré avantage devraient être plus largement partagées. J'ai réfléchi à comment conduire ces entretiens et là mon incroyable collègue, Camilla Gunn, a créé un guide « Travailler avec un cancer ». Ce guide donne des conseils aux patients atteints, à leurs employeurs, à leurs collègues et à leurs soignants, sur comment parler du cancer et des aides professionnelles possibles. Camilla et moi avons contacté d'autres structures pour présenter ce livret et expliquer comment il pourrait aider à dialoguer sur un sujet qui peut être délicat. Et je suis ravie d'annoncer que le livret est de plus en plus utilisé. Donc, quelle devrait être la réponse d'un employeur face à un salarié qui lui annonce sa maladie et qui ignore l'impact que cela aura sur son travail ? Cela devrait être ceci : « Dans la mesure où vous en êtes capable et en avez envie, nous serons ravis de trouver un arrangement vous permettant de continuer à travailler. » Nous devons encourager les personnes atteintes de maladies graves à rester dans le milieu professionnel plutôt que les mettre à l'écart. Je vous ai raconté mon histoire pour que vous sachiez les bienfaits que travailler m'a apportés et changer votre opinion si vous pensez que quelqu'un sous traitement n'est rien autre que fatigué, fragile et ne fait que vomir. Alors oui, c'est vrai parfois, et même souvent, mais j'avais la volonté de travailler autant que je l'avais toujours fait. Et j'ai pu le faire car on m'a donné le choix. Mais plus encore, je vous en parle car, s'il semble évident de laisser le choix, travailler n'est en général pas encouragé, ni même proposé. Pourtant cela devrait. Merci. (Applaudissements)